<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>io.github.santiagocezar.maniatic-launcher</id>
  <name>Maniatic Launcher</name>
  <summary>A launcher for the decompilation of Retro Engine (v5)</summary>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>Sonic</keyword>
    <keyword>Mania</keyword>
    <keyword>RSDK</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
  </categories>
  <description>
    <p>
    A launcher for the decompilation of Retro Engine v5, used in Sonic Mania Plus.
    It allows to run this game natively, and facilitates the installation and development 
    of mods.
    </p>
    <p>
    To play this decompilation, you neeed to own a Steam copy of Sonic Mania (or Plus).
    </p>

    <p>This software is distributed under Fair Use. The Digital Millenium Copyright Act of 1998, in Section 103(f)(3) regarding Reverse Engineering states:</p>
    <p>
      The information acquired through the acts permitted under
      paragraph (1), and the means permitted under paragraph (2),
      may be made available to others if the person referred to in paragraph
      (1) or (2), as the case may be, provides such information or means
      solely for the purpose of enabling interoperability of an independently
      created computer program with other programs, and to the
      extent that doing so does not constitute infringement under this
      title or violate applicable law other than this section.
    </p>
    <p>
    This software contains decompiled code from Sonic Mania, made by Sega Corporation and Evening Star,
    which was adapted to run natively in Linux-based operating systems. It does not
    contain any kind of art (music, graphics) or level layouts from the original game.
    As a result, the software does not work unless the user provides their own copy 
    of Sonic Mania, obtained by their own legal means.
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/santiagocezar/maniatic-launcher/</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>
        https://raw.githubusercontent.com/santiagocezar/maniatic-launcher/main/data/launcher_screenshot.png
      </image>
      <caption>
        A window titled "Sonic Mania Decompilation Project", the background is a tiled silhouette of
        the "Majin Sonic" sprite from that Sonic CD sound test easter egg.

        Inside the window, in big bold letters it says: "Not so fast!", and following below with a
        normal typeface: "The app couldn't find a copy of Sonic Mania installed on Steam. We can't
        legally distribute the assets (sprites, levels, music, etc.) from the game, so you need to
        provide your legal copy of it."

        Links to Steam, Epic Games and Origin are listed below, with a button to import the Data.rsdk
        file manually. In the footer of the window it reads: "Fun is infinite. This application is
        not affiliated with SEGA Corporation."
      </caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>
        https://cdn.sega.com/sonicmania01_0.png
      </image>
      <caption>
        A screenshot of Sonic Mania where Sonic is eager play Green Hill Zone Act 1.
      </caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>
        https://cdn.sega.com/sonicmania02_0.png
      </image>
      <caption>
        A screenshot of Sonic Mania where Sonic is fighting against the double-wrecking-ball boss
        from Green Hill Zone Act 1.
      </caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>
        https://cdn.sega.com/sonicmania04_0.png
      </image>
      <caption>
        A screenshot of Sonic Mania where Sonic lost all his rings after being hit by the microphone
        badnik from Studiopolis Zone Act 1.
      </caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.santiagocezar.maniatic-launcher.desktop</launchable>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0 AND LicenseRef-RDSCLv2=https://github.com/Rubberduckycooly/RSDKv5-Decompilation/blob/master/LICENSE.md</project_license>
  <developer_name>Santiago Cézar</developer_name>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="violence-cartoon">mild</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2022-08-19">
      <description>
        <p>it's time to be a little silly</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
